我是奧利弗•奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年裡  我被困在地獄一般的小島上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回來只有一個目標
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
To save my city.
但要達到目標  我不能像過去一樣成為兇手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
為了紀念我的朋友  我只能偽裝成另一個人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
深切懷念托馬斯•梅林
孝子
成為另一種存在
I must be something else.
《綠箭俠》前情回顧
Previously on "Arrow"...
艾沃殺了莎朵
Ivo killed Shado.
因為我選擇了救你
Because I chose to save you.
殺害了莎朵的人還在逍遙法外
The man who killed Shado is still out there.
他不會逍遙很久的  因為我們要奪下貨船
Not for long. Because we're going to take the freighter.
梅林才是西婭的親生父親
Merlyn is Thea's father.
但我認為你應該親口告訴奧利弗
But I thought you deserved to tell Oliver yourself.
我是不會告訴我兒子任何事情的
I'm not going to tell my son anything.
西婭永遠都不能知道梅林的事
Thea can never find out about Merlyn.
從現在開始  我們再無瓜葛
As of right now, we have no relationship.
我們之間再無關係
You and I are done.
親愛的  你還好嗎
Sweetheart, are you ok?
我們生活中出現的
Every single thing that's gone wrong
所有不愉快都是你的錯
in our lives is your fault.
你給我滾
Now get out.
-對不起  -我讓你滾
- I'm sorry. - I said, get out!
六秒後
In six seconds,
克羅企業
大廳裡的保安會換班
lobby security will undergo a shift change.
到時候  你走到電梯裡去
When that happens, make for the elevator bay.
收到
Copy.
記住我跟你說的
Now, remember what I told you--
時機就是一切
timing is everything.
保持每秒1.3秒的速度
Maintain a pace of 1.3 meters
六秒走到目標處
per second. Six seconds to target.
5  4
5, 4...
克羅企業
就是現在  先生們
Now is the time, gentlemen.
是指紋識別器  我破解不了
It's a fingerprint reader. I can't crack it.
我能
I can.
你們有5.3秒的時間走到東樓梯
You have 5.3 seconds to get down the east stairwell.
別走了
Stop!
我們在幹什麼
What the hell are we doing?
我們拿到了想要的東西
We got what we came for.
他說了等等
He said to wait.
在明處等著嗎  別管了
Out in the open? Forget this.
別這樣  別這樣
Don't do it. Don't do it!
保安發現了我們
Security clocked us!
星城警局嗎  你們得派點警官過來
SCPD? You've got to send some officers here.
上面  三樓  三樓
Up there, third floor. Third floor!
他們通知了星城警局
They've alerted the SCPD.
22秒內從東大廳的出口離開
Exit the east lobby in 22 seconds.
星城警局  放下武器
SCPD! Put your weapons down!
沃爾查克
Walczak!
DC52向搜查小隊呼叫  市中心需要支援
Delta Charlie 52 to search, I need back-up, downtown!
離開這裡  走開
Get out of here. Get out.
讓開  讓開
Move. Move.
一切權力歸人民
Power to the people.
《綠箭》  第二季第十四集
狄格
Dig!
莎拉  對不起
Sara, I'm so sorry.
沒關係  我沒事
It's ok, I'm fine.
讓我看看  讓我看看
Let me see. Let me see.
她在流血  但是傷口不深
She's bleeding, but it's not deep.
真好  我不能再留疤了
Good, I can't take any more scars.
話說  你這是迫擊炮留下的傷
Speaking of... mortar round?
是的  簡易爆炸裝置  在阿富汗的派克迪卡省  眼力不錯
Yeah, IED, the Paktika province in Afghanistan. Good eye.
傷口我很熟
I know my wounds.
手榴彈  在阿爾及爾
Grenade. Algiers.
我從沒被手榴彈炸傷過
I've never been hit by a grenade.
你身上那麼多傷疤  居然沒被手榴彈炸傷過
All those scars, you've never been hit by a grenade?
箭傷  刀傷  刀傷
Arrow, knife, knife.
受過很多槍傷  沒有手榴彈
A lot of bullets, no grenades.
我最近中彈了
I've got myself a new bullet.
九毫米  就在這
Nine millimeter, right there.
38毫米口徑  我主要是劍傷  還有一處矛傷
.38. I'm mostly swords, and a spear.
我有一塊傷疤
I have a scar.
在我嘴裡
It's in my mouth.
16歲時我拔了智齒
I had my wisdom teeth removed when I was 16.
縫了三針  嵌得很緊
Three stitches. They were really badly impacted.
你還是很可愛
You're still cute.
我們該出發了
We should get going.
總不能在自己的歡迎派對上遲到
You don't want to be late for your own welcome home party.
你沒必要給我開派對  奧利
You didn't have to throw me a party, Ollie.
莎拉  死裡逃生  就得開派對
Sara, when you come back from the dead, you get a party.
這是奎恩家的傳統
It's a Queen family tradition.
蘭斯家的傳統是永遠記仇
I don't know how well that's going to work
好像咱家傳統也沒什麼用啊
with the Lance family tradition of holding grudges forever.
她會想通的
She'll come around.
也許吧
Maybe.
也許我們該繼續
And maybe we should keep what's going on
把我倆的事保密
between you and me between us.
為了勞蕾爾
For Laurel's sake.
我明白
I get that.
我連煉獄島和南達爾巴特都挺過來了
I survived Lian Yu and Nanda Parbat,
一個雞尾酒宴會還是應付得來的
I guess I can handle a cocktail party.
那可不一定
That wouldn't be so sure.
我們不可能做到
We're never going to make it.
艾沃有八名全副武裝的保鏢  隨時待命
Ivo has eight guards on deck at all times, all armed.
一旦被看到  就是我們的死期
The second they see us, we're dead.
首先得處理艾沃的防禦系統
Assuming we can deal with Ivo's defenses.
我們怎麼靠近那艘船
How are we going to get close enough to board the ship?
我們可以造個木筏
Maybe we build a raft.
我們得花幾個星期才能砍到足夠的木材
It'll take us weeks to find the timber.
我們沒那麼多時間
We don't have weeks.
我在這座島上待了264天
I've been on this island for 264 days.
我有的是時間
All I have is weeks.
閉嘴
Shut up.
你不用維護我  奧利
You don't have to stick up for me, Ollie.
什麼  不是
What? No,
你們兩個都別說話
both of you shut up.
聽
Listen.
你們聽到了嗎
Do you hear that?
-在下面  -救命
- Hey, down here! - Help!
你讓我們坐在監控攝像頭前面
You left us sitting in front of the security camera.
保安完全可能殺了我們
Guards could have killed us.
你在聽嗎
Are you listening?
如果你們聽我的
If you had simply waited
再靜待五秒鐘
for five more seconds, like you were told,
就沒有人會死
No one would have died.
抱歉  我可不會把自己的生命
Sorry. I wasn't going to bet ten to twenty up in iron heights
賭在你那使用碼錶的技能上
on your skills with a stopwatch.
"所有勇士中最強大的兩個
"The strongest of all warriors
是時間與耐心"
are these two-- time and patience."
什麼
What?
出自《戰爭與和平》
It's from "War and peace."
第1440頁
1,440 pages.
書挺厚的  不過很值得閱讀
It takes a while, but it's worth a read.
托爾斯泰知道耐心是力量的象徵
Tolstoy knew that patience was the epitome of strength.
停下腳步需要勇氣
It takes fortitude to stand still.
在不合時宜的時候行動
Just as it is a sign of weakness or cowardice
是弱者和懦夫的表現
to move when you should not!
聽著
Look.
我們完成了工作  你欠我一個人情
We did the job. You owe me.
死後就一了百了
The dead are owed nothing.
進來吧  進來進來
Ah, come in. Come in, come in.
歡迎回家  莎拉
Welcome home, Sara.
你能來我真是太開心了  跟我來
I'm so happy you're here. Come on.
莎拉  這位是辛
Oh, Sara, this is Sin.
等等  你們兩個認識嗎
Wait, do you two know each other?
不  我們不認識
Uh, no. Uh, we don't.
沒錯  我只是很喜歡那些死而復生的人
Right. I just love when people come back from the dead, you know?
滿足我的戀僵屍癖
Juices my zombie fetish.
我是羅伊
Um, Roy.
我是莎拉
Sara.
走吧
Come on.
抱歉
Sorry.
勞蕾爾  我是奧利
Laurel, it's Ollie.
奧利弗
來電
我希望你能來參加聚會
I hope you're coming to the party.
我聽說你有點生莎拉的氣
I heard that you maybe were a little mad at Sara,
而我...
And I...
她是你的妹妹  你只有這一個妹妹
She's your sister, and--and you only get one.
知道嗎  再見
You know? Bye.
勞蕾爾不來
Laurel is not coming.
也許她需要時間
Well, maybe she just needs time.
是啊
Yeah.
我也需要時間
Yeah, I needed time, too.
當你回來的時候  我...
When you got back, I...
我對你非常嚴厲
Well, I was pretty harsh on you. Hey,
蘭斯先生  你  你不需要
Mr. Lance, you--you don't have to--
我需要這麼做
Oh, I do.
當你和莎拉一起上船出來的時候
When you and Sara went off on your dad's boat,
你還只是一個孩子  你們兩個都是
you were just a kid, both of you were.
無論她能不能回來...
And whether she came back, or...
我太過分了
I was out of line.
你不是殺人犯  奧利弗
You're not a killer, Oliver.
-走吧  -走
- Yeah, - Come on, yeah.
我真為你高興  黛娜
I'm so happy for you, Dinah.
奧利弗失蹤的那五年
Those five years that Oliver was gone,
就像  我失去了我身體的一部分
was...like a piece of me was missing.
我明白你的感覺
I know just what you mean.
-抱歉  -沒關係
- Oh, excuse me. - Of course.
沒想到你會來
I didn't think you'd be here.
這是我家
This is my house.
如果你不想裝作母子情深
And if you don't want to pretend to be mother and son,
那就別在我家辦聚會
then don't throw parties in my home.
媽媽
Mom?
你和奧利之間沒什麼問題吧
Is everything ok with you and Ollie?
當然
Yes, of course.
你知道嗎  我仍然難以相信
You know, I still can't quite believe it.
我從來不敢想像
I never really thought
莎拉會回到我們身邊  昆汀
Sara would come back to us, Quentin.
是的  我知道
Yeah, I know.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我是蘭斯
Lance.
我馬上到
I'll be right there.
工作的事
It's work.
貧民區發生了殺人案件  我...
There's a homicide in the Glades, and I --
我得走了
I better go.
馬上到
I'm on my way.
你怎麼知道我要打來
How did you know I was calling?
因為蘭斯警探也接到了電話
Because detective lance just got the same call.
怎麼在每個案發現場都能見到你倆
What, you guys just show up to every crime scene now?
跟著你來的
I saw you leave.
鑒證科剛從一個叫艾迪•沃爾查克的人身上找到了這個
CSU just pulled this out of a skel I know named Eddie Walczak.
從沒見過這樣的刀
I've never seen a knife life this.
這不是刀  是個分針
It's not a knife, it's a minute hand,
應該是鐘表上的
like from a clock.
幾年前沃爾查克因非法闖入被我逮捕過
I popped Walczak f or B&E a few years back.
今早  他和一個同夥涉嫌一起搶劫殺人案
This morning, he and an accomplice were involved in a robbery homicide.
他們偷了什麼
What'd they steal?
什麼高科技的玩意
Some high-tech gizmo.
科爾德的人管它叫  萬能鑰匙
Kord rep called it a, um, skeleton key.
怎麼  你知道那是什麼嗎
What? You know what it is?
那是軍方用於破解地方智能目標密碼
It was intended as a military tool to aid in code breaking
而發明的一個解碼器
on foreign intelligence targets.
奎恩聯合企業的費利西蒂•斯莫克
Felicity Smoak works at queen consolidated
說企業本來也在研製類似的東西
and she said they were working on something similar...
但奧利弗•奎恩停止了計劃
but Oliver Queen shut it down once he realized
因為意識到了它的作用
what it could be used for.
什麼作用
What?
稍加改進  它就可以打開金庫
It could be modified to open a bank vault,
任何金庫
any bank vault.
但是沃爾查克可沒那麼高智商
Ok, listen -- Walczak's small-time on a good day.
我懷疑他甚至都不會用這玩意
I mean, I doubt he'd even know how to use this thing,
更不要說能闖進科爾德把它偷出來了
let alone break into a place like Kord and steal it on his own.
沃爾查克只是個傀儡
Walczak was just the muscle.
我們要找的是幕後主使
We need to find the brain.
雙腳間距拉開
Plant your feet.
這樣才站得穩
Strong foundation.
這樣出拳才更有力
Equals stronger punch.
不錯
Nice.
你要是為了防身  我建議你練詠春
If this is for self defense, I'd recommend wing chun.
它的原理是借力打力
It uses your opponent's strength against him.
很適合身材嬌小的人群
So it's ideal for smaller people...
比如我們
like us.
看來你一定照顧得好自己咯
You seem like you can take care of yourself just fine.
你沒事吧
Are you ok?
萬能鑰匙找得怎麼樣了
Where are we with the skeleton key?
而且你  怎麼穿成這樣
And what... are you wearing?
我只是想...
I just thought I'd...
正在將沃爾查克的已知同夥
I'm cross referencing Walczak's known associates
和國家安全局解密專家的監視名單做對比
with decryption experts on the NSA watch list,
但是需要時間
but it's taking some time,
問題在於沒時間了
which we don't have.
鑰匙不僅是個解密器
Ok, the key is not just a code breaker.
落進壞人手裡  它完全就是武器
in the wrong hands, it's a weapon.
那個殺掉沃爾查克的人
whoever killed Walczak,
奇怪到用鐘表零件殺人的人
in addition to finding creepy uses for clock parts,
很會掩藏蹤跡
is very good at covering his tracks.
我們很幸運  搜查追蹤
Lucky for us, uncovering tracks
正是你的強項
is what you're very good at.
是啊
Right.
果然壞了
Of course.
他快死了
He's barely alive.
我們還有醫療用品嗎
Do you have medical supplies at the fuselage?
應該  不多了
We have -- we have some.
快去拿  我應付得了
Just go. I'll be fine.
我開始後悔給你一把鑰匙了
I'm really starting to regret giving you a key.
抱歉我沒去參加派對
I'm sorry I bailed on the party.
我猜到了
Ah, I figured you wouldn't make an appearance.
終於有人理解我了
Finally, someone understands.
我還沒厲害到能理解你
Well, I, uh, I wouldn't go that far.
但是我理解  莎拉沒告訴我們她還活著
But I understand how Sara keeping it a secret
確實很傷人
that she was still alive could hurt.
因為我也傷心
'Cause it hurt me, too.
怎麼聽起來你要說"但是"了
I sense a "But" Coming in my future.
沒錯  但是我希望你能原諒此事
But, yes, but I need you to move past it.
勞蕾爾
Laurel.
來個家庭聚餐吧
A family dinner.
也是個和解的機會嘛
It's a chance to reconcile.
我不想和莎拉和解
I don't want to reconcile with Sara.
我沒說是為了讓你倆和解
I'm not talking about you and Sara.
我是說想讓...
I'm talking about...
我和你媽和解
me and your mom.
你什麼意思
What do you mean?
我不知道該怎麼說
I don't know to describe it.
就是感覺我們倆不對勁
It was like there was, um...signals,
直覺吧
and feelings.
我也不知道怎麼回事
And I'm not exactly sure what's going on,
但我想要是我們一家人在一起
but I figured if we were all together as a family,
也許能讓她想起我們曾經那麼幸福
maybe it would remind her of how happy we were.
懂嗎
You know?
我也不知道  也許吧...
I mean, I don't know, maybe it...
我是不是很傻
is it stupid?
不會  這...
No, it...
我是警員DC52  請講
Go for Delta-Charlie 52.
發生搶劫殺人案
415 in progress.
地點是維德米銀行  副隊要求全小隊過去
Widmeer bank. Lieutenant requesting all units.
警員DC52收到
Delta-Charlie 52 responding.
我得走了
I got to go.
今天晚上
Tonight.
八點半
8:30.
-喊大家過來  -怎麼了
- Tell everyone to be here. - What?
你家太小了
Well, your place is too small,
我無意冒犯  只是你家挺亂的  所以
and, no offense, it's kind of a mess, so...
- 寶貝  -好啦
- Oh, sweetheart. - OK.
我愛你  甜心
I love you, sweetheart.
-設備準備好了  -3.2秒
- Device is hot. - 3.2 seconds.
九十秒內全力搶錢去吧
Extract as much money as you can in 90 seconds.
停  出去
Stop! Get out of there!
我們還有二十秒的時間
We've still got 20 seconds.
沒有時間了
No, you don't.
撤
Come on!
他們已經逃了
They're already gone!
我估計知道在哪
I think I have an idea where.
萬能鑰匙是通過正交頻分的無線信號起作用的
The Skeleton Key operates on an OFDM wireless signal.
我收到了銀行邊上的
I'm picking up a transmission signal
一條小巷發出的傳輸信號
in the alley next to the bank.
但是你們不會去那的
But you won't be heading there.
什麼聲音
What was that?
他黑進了我們的傳輸信號
He's hacked our transmission.
我的同伴可能會撤到巷子
My associates may be headed to the alley,
但從新月環來的910路公交
but the 910 bus from Crescent Circle
十字路口暢通
就要和星光快遞的火車相撞了
is about to collide with the Starlight Freight Express.
十字路口警報
我的天  他說中了
Oh, my god, he's right,
910路公交正開在艾摩斯特街的路上
the 910's headed for the track at Amherst.
要我看  你總不能同時出現在兩個地方
By my calculations, you can't be in two places at once.
他不知道我們有兩個人
He doesn't know there's two of us.
910路  新月環
快  快
Come on! Come on!
訪問拒絕
他進入了交通部的網絡
He's in the transit department network!
十字路口警報
他黑進了信號系統
He's--he's hacked the signaling system.
我沒法放置十字路口的路障
I--I can't get the crossing barriers down!
公交車上有對講機
Those buses have radios.
你能黑進去  告訴司機停車嗎
Can you break in, wave them off?
不能  他攔住我了
No, he's keeping me out.
時鐘國王敲了兩次鐘
媒體沒取昵稱之前  這事都毫無真實感
I guess it's not real until the media comes up with a nickname.
我開酒吧怎麼能沒有調酒師呢
How can I run a bar without any bartenders?
說到這個  你怎麼能
For that matter, how can you quit
一聲不吭就跑人了呢
without giving me notice?
不  開門前一小時才告知我
No, one hour before opening
就不叫做提前告知  曼蒂
is not notice, Mandy.
我能和你談談嗎
Can I talk to you for a second?
我去金髮妞的房間裡待一會
I'm going to go use the little blonde's room.
都還好嗎
Everything ok?
你說呢
You tell me.
除了派對
Other than the party,
我還沒見過你有在家待過一整周
I haven't seen you at home all week.
我可是個大忙人
I've been busy.
總裁的事情多得讓我都沒時間做別的了
Being a CEO doesn't leave me a lot of free time.
是嗎  在我看來你比較像是在躲著媽媽
Yeah, looks to me a whole lot like you're avoiding mom.
我沒在躲她
I'm not avoiding mom.
你該慶幸自己的生活並不是充斥著謊言
You're lucky your life does not revolve around lying.
西婭
Thea.
一切都很好
Everything's fine.
秘密是最先開始導致
You know, it's secrets
家庭四分五裂的原因  奧利
that pushed this family apart in the first place, Ollie.
閃電妞  閃電妞  我說真的
Speedy, Speedy. Really.
一切都好
Everything's fine.
現在什麼情況
What do we know?
他黑進了我們的無線信號
He hacked into our frequency,
不知道他怎麼獲得了遠程訪問權限
somehow gained remote access,
我升級了防火墻
but I upgraded our firewall.
現在除非他有火箭炮
Now he won't be able to
否則他是不可能黑進我們的通信了
talk into our comms even if he had a bazooka.
我是說  是電腦通信這方面的火箭炮
You know... computer science-wise.
很好
Good.
這東西可能會幫我們抓到他
I think I have something that might help us track him down.
可以給我拿去實驗室做測試
I can run that to the lab.
我在貨船上曾花了一年時間研究血液基因變異
I spent a year on the freighter studying genetic blood anomalies.
顯微鏡實驗方面我也算是行家了
I kind of know my way around a microscope.
細胞被嚴重破壞
There's some significant cell damage
血小板數量極低
and the platelet count is extremely low.
費利西蒂  我能借用下你的電腦嗎
Felicity, can I use your computer?
麥克格瑞格綜合症  這是一種遺傳缺失
Macgregor's syndrome. It's a genetic defect
會在肺部積水
that creates fluid build-up in the lungs,
導致缺氧和多器官衰竭
which leads to oxygen deprivation and multi system organ failure.
到晚期了
It's terminal.
這個綜合症也許能幫我們確認他的身份
But the syndrome may give us a way to ID him.
患麥克格瑞格綜合症的人極少
People with macgregor's are extremely rare,
患有此綜合症
and people with macgregor's and
有計算機學位的人更少見
a degree in computer science are even more rare.
威廉•塔克曼  前編碼工程師
William Tockman. Former encryption engineer at,
好戲來了  在科爾德實業工作
wait for it-- Kord Enterprises.
這麼做的意義在哪裡
What's the point?
他在把錢花光前就死了
He'll be dead before he can spend all the money.
他不是為了自己而去偷錢的
He's not stealing the money for himself.
他是為了他的家人  特別是他的姐姐
He's using it for his family. His sister, specifically.
她有囊胞性纖維症  需要肺移植
She's got cystic fibrosis and needs a lung transplant.
把地址給我  謝謝
Give me an address, please.
納爾遜路52號
52 Nelson Way.
這區域看起來可不太像是住宅區
This area doesn't look very residential.
就是這兒了
There.
那是塔克曼的車
That's Tockman's ride.
塔克曼不在這兒  只留下了些裝置
Tockman's not here. Just some device.
我在查了  卡車裡的那個裝置正在傳輸
I'm on it. Whatever's in the truck
和塔克曼在銀行用的相同的正交頻分復用信號
is transmitting the same OFDM signal Tockman used at the bank.
-你能追蹤嗎  -已經開始了
- Can you trace it? - As we speak.
信號追蹤到了...我們的網絡
It's leading... back to our network.
塔克曼盜用了我的入侵線路  這是個陷阱
Tockman's piggybacking off my hack. It's a trap.
他想要入侵我們的網絡
He--he's trying to break into our network.
我不是想入侵
I'm not trying.
我就在入侵
I am.
你在哪兒
Where are you?
你在家嗎
Are you home?
你安全嗎
Are you safe?
你感到安全的一個地方
Somewhere you think you're safe...
在一個沒有窗戶來讓人爬進的地方嗎
Somewhere without windows for anyone to creep through?
有可能是地下
Underground, perhaps?
你覺得沒人能找到你嗎
You think no one can get to you?
你覺得藏在安全避風港裡
You think no one can touch you
就沒人會碰到你嗎
in the safety of your hidey hole?
費利西蒂
Felicity...
但是我可以
But I can.
有多槽糕
How bad?
塔克曼用萬能鑰匙
Tockman used the skeleton key
侵入了我們的防火墻
to penetrate our firewall.
並且重新編碼了我們的安全系統
And recode our security.
基本上他讓我們的系統去自毀
Basically, he told our system to commit suicide.
結果還成功了
And it did.
漫畫中的超級大惡人
精彩  同步信號之王
Bravo, clock king.
莎拉在塔克曼的人可以卷錢而逃之前
Sara stopped Tockman's men before they could
制止了他們
get away with the cash.
所以塔克曼一定會再幹一票
So Tockman is going to be looking for another score.
或許我們應該給他創造機會
Maybe we should give him one.
你能不能打給沃爾特讓他清算出
Would you call Walter and have him liquidate
奎恩集團股票裡的五十萬股
500,000 shares of QC stock?
把現金放進我在星城國民銀行的保險庫中
Put it in cash in my vault at Starling National,
讓他今晚就做
and ask him to do it tonight.
如果塔克曼想再幹一票的話
If Tockman wants to make another score...
誰還能比忽然有大把現金的
Who better to rob than a suddenly
奧利弗•奎恩更值得去搶呢
cash flush Oliver Queen?
那如果他不上當怎麼辦
And what if he doesn't take the bait?
有道理  八十萬股好了
That's a good point. Make it 800,000 shares.
好的  我能做些什麼呢
Ok. What can I do?
赴約去吃晚餐
Go to your dinner.
你的家人或許在等著你呢
Your family's probably waiting for you.
是啊
Right.
在勞蕾爾家吃晚餐
Dinner at Laurel's.
這件事更重要
This is more important.
你在這裡無能無力  莎拉
You can't do anything here, Sara.
你的家人也很重要
Your family's important, too.
是的
Yeah.
你應該赴約
You should go.
你能跟我一塊去嗎
Will you go with me?
什麼
What?
我知道我想讓一家人團聚很久了
I know I've wanted us all to get together for a while now.
只是現在真到了這個地步  我很緊張
It's just, now that it's actually here, I'm nervous.
上一次我見到勞蕾爾的時候  並不順利
I mean, last time I saw Laurel, it...didn't go very well,
而且
And...
如果有人作伴的話會很有幫助
It'd be helpful to not have to go alone.
我或許應該待在這裡
I should probably stay here.
你在這兒又能幫什麼忙呢
What is it exactly you think you can do here to help?
如果需要我們就打電話
Call if you need us.
好的
Yep.
這不是你的錯  費利西蒂
You know, it's not your fault, Felicity.
是嗎  你們中還有誰能
Really? Which one of the rest of you
提供安全維護
put up the security safeguards?
也許如果是莎拉的話
Maybe if it been Sara,
我們現在就不會一團糟了
we wouldn't be in this mess.
我知道我們沒有談過這個
Now, I know we haven't talked about this,
但是他們倆在一起你一定很難受吧
but it must be difficult for you seeing them together.
這不是他們倆在一起的問題
This isn't about them being together.
這是我自己的問題  莎拉可以分析血液
This is about me. Ok, Sara can analyze blood.
拳打腳踢  她無所不能
She can kick ass. She can do anything.
唯一一件我應該做好的事情
And the one thing I'm supposed to be good at,
我也悲劇地搞砸了
I'm failing at miserably.
現在既然有了她  還需要我幹什麼呢
And why do you even need me now that you have her?
因為你是無可取代的  費利西蒂
Because you're irreplaceable, Felicity.
我還有很多事要做
I have a lot of work to do.
勞蕾爾  莎拉來了
Laurel, Sara's here.
你好  媽媽
Hey, mom.
你好
Hi.
奧利弗  謝謝
Oliver. Well, thank you,
花很漂亮
These are lovely.
謝謝
Thank you.
我怎麼不記得你也姓蘭斯呢
I don't remember your last name being Lance.
其實我也不想毀了你們的家庭聚餐
Well, yeah, I certainly didn't want to crash your family dinner,
但是我剛好在路上遇到莎拉
But then...sara and I ran into each other,
她邀請我來
and she mentioned it.
我告訴他爸爸會做最拿手的燴雞塊
And I told him how dad was making his famous chicken cacciatore.
實際上  抱歉
Actually--excuse me!
我們要  奧利弗
We're, uh, we're--oliver.
你好  蘭斯先生
Hey, Mr. Lance.
是的  晚飯只能吃匹薩了  真是抱歉
Yeah. Um, we're having pizza. I'm sorry.
我把晚飯弄砸了
I had a little incident in the kitchen.
如果六年都沒過碰烤箱
I guess that's what happens when you haven't
搞砸也就不奇怪了
used an oven in six years.
來塊兒匹薩吧
Want to grab a slice?
我正要把雞肉塊壘成塔狀
Yeah, when I was pitching a tower of caccitore--
沒錯  是燴雞塊塔
a cacciatore tower, yeah.
您還在教書嗎  蘭斯夫人
Are you still teaching, Mrs. Lance?
是的  在中央城市大學
Yes, I am. Greek and medieval history
教希臘歷史和中世紀歷史
at Central City University.
你也該考慮遞交辭職信了吧
You could probably give them notice.
我為什麼要那麼做
Why would I do that?
我的意思是  你要搬回星城了  對嗎
Well, I mean, you're going to come back to Starling, right?
不
No.
我沒打算搬回星城  昆汀
I'm not moving back to Starling, Quentin.
莎拉回來了
Well, Sara's back.
我在那有新的生活
I have a new life in Central city
很棒的工作
and I have a wonderful job.
工作在哪兒都有啊
Well, there's jobs here.
不只是工作
More than a job.
我認識了  一個人
Um...I have... someone.
這樣  那恭喜你了
Oh... congratulations.
其實這挺好的  媽媽
You know, it's great, mom.
你應該過得快樂些
You deserve to be happy.
大家都應該過得快樂些
Everybody does.
告訴我這不是真的
You've got to be kidding me.
什麼
What?
你才回來多久  一個禮拜
You've been back like, what, a week?
你們甚至都不否認一下  是嗎
And you're not even denying it.
沒有那麼簡單
It's...it's complicated.
當然了  有你怎麼可能簡單
Of course it is. It's you.
勞蕾爾  拜託了
Laurel, please.
爸爸  你的處境也好不到哪去
Dad, you are no better than they are.
你真的以為
I mean, what did you think,
媽媽會心甘情願等你的雞塊
mom was just going to sit around and wait for you for six years
六年時間嗎
to bake her chicken?
勞蕾爾  別說了
Ok, Laurel, enough!
還是期待她會回心轉意
And sweep her back off her feet?
你說夠了沒有
Enough, ok?
沒錯  你知道嗎  我是夠了
Yeah, you know what, it is enough!
吃完了就滾出這裡
Invite yourselves out when you're done.
我的錢包
My wallet.
好的
Ok.
這是我女兒
She's my daughter.
她12歲
She's 12.
我需要和她講話
I need to talk to her.
你的對講機壞掉了
Your radio's broken.
她媽媽在她嬰兒時就死了
Her mother died just after she got out of diapers.
死於癌症
Cancer.
除了我
And without me...
連一個照顧她的人都沒有了
she's not going to have anybody to look after her.
所以
So...
我知道我並不認識你
I know I don't know you.
你也不認識我
And I know you don't know me.
但是
But...
求求你一定要確保我女兒平安
please make sure my daughter's OK.
求求你
Please.
你簡直令人難以置信
You are unbelievable!
是你告訴我  我需要修復
You lecture me on how I need to repair my relationship with Sara
我和莎拉之間被你破壞的關係
when you're the one who messed it up in the first place.
就因為你倆有一腿
By screwing her!
而現在你要重蹈覆轍
And now you're doing it again.
你說得對  是我的錯
You're right. This is all my fault.
沒錯  是你的錯
Yeah. Yeah, yes, it is.
你丟了工作  開始吸毒酗酒
And is you losing your job, doing drugs and being a drunk,
也是我的錯嗎
is that my fault?
是你家人的錯嗎
Is that your family's fault,
還是要歸咎于湯米的死呢
or are you going to blame Tommy for dying?
去你的  奧利弗
Screw you, Oliver.
自始至終我都是支持你的
I have stood by you through everything--
無論是你酒駕被罰  丟掉工作
the DUI, losing your job,
還是你努力想讓我母親被判死刑時  勞蕾爾
and Laurel, I was concerned about your well-being
我一直都在為你的身心考慮
when you were trying to get my mother the death penalty!
是啊  你可真是個正直的人啊
Yeah, you've been a real stand-up kind of guy.
勞蕾爾  你以為只有你自己
Laurel, do you think you're the only one
很不好過嗎
that is having a hard time?!
你以為只有你一個人有家庭問題嗎
Do you think you're the only one with family issues?
你完全...你完全不知道
You have-- you have no idea
我家裡現在發生了什麼事
what is going on with my family right now.
但我還站在這裡
But I am still standing here.
而你還在指責除你以外的所有人
And you are still blaming everybody but yourself.
你說夠了嗎
Are you done?
是的
Yeah.
是的  我夠了
Yeah, I'm done.
我受指責受夠了
I'm done taking the blame.
也關心夠了
And I'm done caring.
你去喝一杯吧
Why don't you go have a drink?
喝醉點  去吧
Get wasted, go...
去威登吧
Go to Verdant.
我買單
I'll pay for it.
我愛你愛了半生
I have loved you for half my life.
但我追夠你了
But I'm done running after you.
你看見費利西蒂了嗎
Have you seen Felicity?
沒有  等等  怎麼了
No. Wait, why?
我去大貝利漢堡店買了些外賣
I went to Big Belly to get some take-out.
我回來的時候  她就不在了
When I came back, she was gone.
我好幾個小時沒看見她了
I haven't seen her for hours.
塔克曼上鉤了  就是你讓沃爾特存的那筆錢
Tockman took the bait. The money you had Walter deposit.
我在星城國民銀行讀取他的信號
I'm reading his signal at Starling National.
等等  你怎麼知道的
Wait...how do you know that?
-因為我就在這裡  -什麼
- Because I'm here. - What?!
你在這兒幹什麼
What are you doing here?
我在追蹤塔克曼
I'm tracking Tockman.
他弄壞了我們的電腦  所以我用銀行的電腦
He fried our computers, so I'm using the bank's
追蹤萬能鑰匙的信號
to trace the skeleton key's signature.
那夾克是怎麼回事
And the jacket?
我很冷
I was cold.
狄格爾  把她弄出去
Diggle, get her out of here.
塔克曼弄壞了銀行的安保系統
Tockman disabled the bank's security system.
我重新弄好了
I re-abled it.
他們在阻截我們的出路
They're blocking our way out.
我去處理他們
I'll deal with them.
塔克曼的信號很強
Tockman's signal's strong.
他就在這兒  很近
He's here, he's close.
找到他  費利西蒂
Find him, Felicity.
不需要
No need.
我告訴你們我的準確位置
I'll tell you exactly where I am.
我無處不在
I'm everywhere.
現在  我正在關注地下
At the moment, I'm particularly focused on the sub-level.
確切的說  是燃氣管道
The gas mains, specifically.
天啊  他關閉了煤氣排放
Oh, my god. He shut down the gas main release.
這為什麼不好
And why is that bad?
積聚多了會引起爆炸
The build-up could cause an explosion.
會的  會炸毀周圍三個街區
It will. It'll blow up three square blocks.
不  不會的
No, it won't.
等等  塔克曼太過於炫耀了
Wait. Tockman overplayed his hand.
煤氣管道在全市聯網中  那是我的地盤
The gas main's in the city's network, that's where I live.
我該理解你的話嗎
Am I supposed to understand that?
他想要炸飛我們
Ohh. In trying to blow us up,
這也給了我一個扳倒他的機會
he gave me a way to track him down.
這我理解
That I understood.
發生了什麼
What's happening?
小心
Look out!
你都不知道我為什麼要這麼做
You don't even know why I'm doing this.
錢不是給我的
The money's not for me!
我做這一切都是為了她
I'm doing this all for her!
那也不對
Doesn't make it right.
光陰似箭[拉丁文]
Tempus fugit.
光陰似箭
Time flies.
那是什麼
What the hell was that?
他的手機
His cell phone.
我給他安裝了
I uploaded the same virus
他裝在我鑄造廠裡裝備上同樣的病毒
he used on my gear in the foundry.
我沒殺死他吧
I didn't just kill him, did I?
只是把他弄昏了
Just knocked him out.
-我們做到了  -是你做到了
- We did it. - You did it.
你確定不想去醫院
Are you sure you don't want to go to the hospital?
你們就從不去醫院
You guys never go to the hospital.
另外  狄格給了我幾片那種阿司匹林
Besides, Dig gave me some of those aspirins.
你在旋轉嗎
Are you spinning?
止疼藥
-阿司匹林  -鹽酸羥考酮
- Aspirin? - Oxycodone.
如果不是你那麼勇敢
I wouldn't be here
我現在就不在這裡了  謝謝
if you hadn't been so brave. Thank you.
沒事
It was nothing.
我一直想說我為某人擋了一顆子彈
I've always wanted to say I've taken a bullet for someone,
現在我可以說了
and now I can.
所以說真的  我該感謝你
So really I should be thanking you.
都好了
All done.
不嚴重  但你依舊會留疤
Not bad, but you're still going to have a scar.
我自己的傷疤
My own scar.
好啊
Yay.
你還好嗎
You all right?
狄格爾說你可能感覺有一點...
Diggle had mentioned that maybe you were feeling...
被忽視了
a little left out.
什麼  沒有
What? No.
我只是...
I was just...
習慣了做你的女人
used to being your girl.
不是你的那種女人
I mean, not your girl-girl.
是你的女人
Your girl.
我知道這是同一個詞
I know it sounds like the same word,
但對我來說含義不同
but it means something different in my head.
你永遠都是我的女人  費利西蒂
You will always be my girl, Felicity.
我能再吃一片阿司匹林嗎
Can I have another one of those aspirins?
威登酒吧
嘗嘗這個
Try this.
不錯吧
Good, huh?
真的很不錯
It's really good.
你怎麼在這裡調酒呢
And what are you doing back here mixing drinks?
西婭雇了我
Thea hired me.
我是新的調酒師了
I am the new bartender.
上大學的時候我做過調酒師  而且
I bartended in college, and, uh, well,
對於簡歷亮點是國際殺手的人來說
it's kind of hard to get a job
找工作好像有點困難
when international assassin is the highlight of you resume.
你會做得很好的
You're going to do great.
來自西婭的短信: 家裡出事了
我得回趟家
I have to go home.
有什麼事嗎
Is everything ok?
希望沒有
I hope so.
你可以放心地走
You can go.
我來這不是要殺她的
I'm not here to kill her or anything.
我還記得你以前在一家
I remember you used to bartend
很破的酒吧裡做調酒師
at that skeevy bar with the...
那裡地上到處都是花生皮
peanut shells all over the floor.
奧博麗薇酒吧
Oblivion.
沒錯
Right.
我不是來這喝酒的
I'm not here for a drink or anything.
那你來這幹什麼
Then why are you here?
因為我覺得
Because I realized that...
我好像也上了那艘船
that I went on that boat with you, too.
而且
And...
這些年來
I've been slowly
我也慢慢地沉了下去
drowning for all of these years.
經歷過各種心碎
And after every heartbreak or
挫折  失敗之後
set-back or loss...
我沉到了黑暗的海底
I sank deeper into the dark water.
但當我見到你時
And so when I saw you,
你是那麼美麗
so beautiful,
那麼充滿活力
and so alive,
我才意識到這些我都沒有
I realized that I'm not those things.
不再有了
Not anymore.
所以  求你了
So please...
求你不要恨我  莎拉
please don't hate me, Sara.
求你了
Please.
天啊  我想死你了
God. I missed you.
我以為什麼事都不能讓你掉眼淚呢
Didn't think anything could make you cry.
看來我沒有你想的那麼堅強
Guess I'm not as tough as you thought.
那
So...
你這毀了的煙熏妝是怎麼回事
why the running mascara?
我剛才
I had--
我剛才跟我姐姐見面了
I just had a moment with my sister.
是一次很好的見面
It was a good one.
那就好
That's good.
雖然勞蕾爾是我的姐姐
Hey, Laurel's my big sister.
但我也願意有一個你這樣的妹妹
I still have room for a little one.
真好
Good.
我不知道如果沒有你我會怎樣
I don't know what I'd do without you.
你不用知道的
Well, you won't have to find out.
我要去找羅伊了
I'm going to go find Roy.
我們在比賽時
2008年5月10日
找到了
Got it.
太晚了
It's too late.
他已經死了
He's gone.
我們都會死在這裡
We're all going to die here.
像他一樣
Just like him.
不  不會的
No, we're not.
我想我找到了上貨船的辦法
I think I found our way on to the freighter.
降落傘
Parachute.
西婭
Thea!
奧利弗  怎麼了
Oliver. What's wrong?
一切都好嗎
Is everything all right?
西婭給我發短信說家裡出事了
Thea texted me there was an emergency at the house.
沒出事  我正在開會
No emergency. I'm in the middle of a meeting
西婭都沒在家裡
and Thea's not even here.
那她為什麼
Well, then why would she...
-我真不敢相信她竟然這麼做了  -做什麼
- I can't believe she would do this. - Do what?
她這是強迫我們倆坐下來談談
She's trying to force us to talk
因為她感覺到了我們之間緊張的氣氛
because she's sensing the tension between us.
你跟她說了什麼
And what did you tell her?
什麼也沒說
Nothing.
那是為了保護她
To protect her.
不是為了你
Not you.
奎恩夫人  一切都好嗎
Mrs. Queen. Is everything ok?
是的  謝謝你關心
Yes, thank you.
我兒子來看我了
Uh, my son just dropped by.
奧利弗  來見見斯萊德•威爾遜
Oliver, I'd like you to meet Slade Wilson.
很高興見到你
It's a pleasure to meet you...
奎恩先生
Mr. Queen.